# DAVID EISENMENGER

**UX DESIGNER & RESEARCHER** 

www.eisenmenger.co david@eisenmenger.co

## **ABOUT ME**

A user experience designer and researcher with a diverse background in product design, social work, and healthcare management. My focus is to solve problems with solutions that create a seamless user experience, make people happy, and add value to the product. My approach uses human-centered design in eliciting user needs and goals working creatively and collaboratively toward solutions.

#### **SKILLS**

Research Interview Survey Content Strategy Usability Testing

Design

Persona

Journey Mapping

Wireframing

Prototyping

Web Design

Tools

Axure RP, Balsamiq Sketch, InVision

Photoshop, Illustrator

InDesign OptimalSort Salesforce VS Code

Languages
HTML
CSS

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### Freelance Design

Dec 2017 - Present

#### User Experience Designer

End to end research and design to create delightful experiences and products. My process involves eliciting client needs, empathizing with users, exploring user goals, synthesizing insights, designing interactions, prototyping, guide an iterative process to delivery. Recent projects include mobile and web.

# Friendship Health and Rehab

Feb 2016 - April 2019

Director of Social Services

Drove customer experience delivery Enhanced patient care related to social services from the 15th percentile (national) to "deficiency free" status in all 42 areas of Quality of Care as measured by CMS annual survey. (2016-2019)

#### Signature Healthcare, LLC

May 2013 - Feb 2016

#### Director of Education, Research, and Programming

Researched and developed programs and products for Inc 5000 healthcare organization. Directed projects from inception to delivery including: Diversity and Inclusion product for care staff.. Emotional Intelligence training delivered to network of 113 facilities. Palliative Care program piloted in four U.S. states.

#### Signature Healthcare, LLC

Oct 2009 - May 2013

**Director of Spirituality** 

Led initiatives focused on patient and staff wellbeing. In a high turnover field, average monthly nursing turnover reduced by a 3% in 12 month period. CMS deficiency free annual surveys 2012, 2013.

#### **EDUCATION**

User Experience Design May 2018 - June 2019

Springboard

Front End Web Development Sept 2017 - Mar 2018

Code Louisville

M.A. Marriage and Family Therapy
Louisville Presbyterian Theological Seminary

Aug 2005 - May 2007

B.A. Peace and Global Studies Aug 1999 - May 2001 Earlham College

# DAVID EISENMENGER

**UX DESIGNER & RESEARCHER** 

www.eisenmenger.co david@eisenmenger.co

# PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Coaching
Creative Problem Solving
Emotional Intelligence
Interviewing
Leadership Development
Program Development
Strategic Planning
Teaching
Teambuilding
Training and Facilitation
User Empathy

#### **AWARDS**

Valedictorian Signature HealthCARE Operational Leadership and Management -2012

Hall of Fame Signature HealthCARE

Better Care Award Norton Healthcare 2009

#### **MEMBERSHIPS**

UXPA International AIGA

#### SELECTED PROJECTS

#### WorldWater

User Experience Design for Mobile

A non governmental organization (NGO) with operations in the United States and Ecuador asked me to redesign their website. The organization's goal was to increase giving and engagement and attract new users. I designed a minimal viable product utilizing mobile first design that streamlines the giving process and leverages social media to allow users to engage others in giving. My Roles: UX Researcher, Information Architect, UI Designer. Methods Used: Surveying, Interviewing, Card Sort, Sketching, Wireframing, Prototyping, Visual Design

## Spark! Diversity and Inclusion Product Design

Spark! is a facilitator led training program developed for an Inc 5000 healthcare company. I led the development of the product from inception to delivery. The concept's design incorporates empathy building, diversity and inclusion awareness using gamification and interpersonal interaction. The program is structured in six free standing 15 minute training modules to be delivered in the staff members' working environment. Each module is designed from the perspectives of healthcare workers and encourages discussion and storytelling. Program assets include: facilitator guide, learner guide, game board, and cards. My Roles: Product Designer, Product Manager. Methods Used: Interviewing, Content Strategy, Mockups, Prototyping, Usability Testing

## Digital Inclusion Design Jam User Experience Research

I served as part of a team of 20 researchers tasked to create potential solutions to issues with digital inclusion in the metropolitan area of Louisville, KY. My research partner I interviewed people who were potential customers of low cost internet programs. We distilled insights and shared this data during the discovery phase of our work. These insights were collected and synthesized as lean user personas. Content from the interviews was incorporated into the "customer" persona. Challenge statements from the discovery phase were organized into Opportunity Areas. I served as part of a design group focused on opportunities within the low cost internet sign up process. The results of the Design Jam were presented at a meeting with representatives from the National Digital Inclusion Alliance (NDIA), corporate stakeholders and city officials. My Role: UX Researcher. Methods Used: Interviewing, Persona, Journey Mapping.